whoisxmlapi.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy - Whois XML API

###  Your Consent 

By using our site, you consent to our website's privacy policy. 

###  Terms and Conditions 

In addition to this webpage, please visit our Terms and Conditions section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website at <https://www.whoisxmlapi.com/terms-of-service.php>

###  What information do we collect? 

We collect information from you when you become a member of our site by registering your information in order to receive an account with us. The only other time we prompt you to collect personal secure information is when you place an order on our site. 

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name or e-mail address. You may also visit our site anonymously at your discretion. 

###  What do we use your information for? 

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways: to process transactions. 

Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your written consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested. 

###  Do we disclose any information to outside parties? 

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety. Non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Non-personally identifiable information is information that on its own cannot identify a person. This can include Device IDs, isolated IP addresses and/or Dynamic IP addresses, as well as cookies. 

According to EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) IP addresses and Dynamic IP addresses are considered Personal Data but are not considered identifiable information when used alone. As part of our compliance with GDPR we will never provide personally identifiable information to outside parties other than for the express purposes of processing your transaction. 

###  Do we use cookies? 

We do not use cookies. 

###  How do we protect your information? 

Private information such as credit cards, social security numbers, billing or shipping information, etc. are never stored on our servers and are always removed after a transaction has taken place on our website. We use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) when performing transactions or becoming a member. This same technology is applied to every transaction process. Providers that participate in our Payment Gateway database gain access to necessary transaction information* by providing legal consent to keep personally identifiable information and sensitive financial information confidential. All participants within our Payment Gateway database are held accountable and responsible for keeping your information not only secure during the transaction process but also private, and are also subject to legal consequence, not excluding jail time for any breach. 

*Necessary transaction information includes but is not limited to, payment methods, billing and shipping information, name, address, phone number, and/or other relevant information needed to perform a transaction for goods and services. 

###  Children's Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children's Online Privacy Protection Act). We do not for any reason authorize the use of our site as a registered member or paying customer to anyone under 13 years of age, nor do we collect any information knowingly or willfully from anyone under 13 years of age. 

###  California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance 

We are not required by law to comply with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. Because we hold your privacy to the highest standard, we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. This means we will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent. As part of the California Online Privacy Protection Act, all users of our site may make any changes to their information at anytime by logging into their account and going to the 'My Account' page. By utilizing this option, you are able to keep your account current or make changes at your own discretion to alter what personal information is securely and privately registered online. 

###  Changes to our Privacy Policy 

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date below. 

This policy was last modified on 05/01/2018.
